College of Arts and Sciences Collection, 1937-1973
University of Houston Libraries
College of Arts and Sciences Records
1937-1973
University of Houston. College of Arts and Sciences
The College of Arts and Sciences, created in 1942, consisted of three divisions: the Division of Cultural Arts, the Division of Sciences, and the Division of Social Sciences. The College of Arts and Sciences continued as the central instructional unit of the University of Houston until 1975 when it was divided into three colleges: the College of Humanities and Fine Arts, the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics, and the College of Social Sciences. This collection consists of records relating to all aspects of the College of Arts and Sciences. Materials date from 1937 to 1973, with the bulk dating from 1963 to 1973. Materials include correspondence, reports, forms, reading files, minutes, and a large variety of other reference and background items relating to the College of Arts and Sciences and its various departments and divisions.
29 boxes; 28.75 linear feet
1977-001
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Organization History
From its inception as a four-year institution in 1934 until the 1942-1943 academic year, the University of Houston consisted of the General College and the Junior College. All areas of academic study at the upper levels were pursued within the General College, while the Junior College provided more vocational and technical training. With the 1942-44 catalog, a new organizational plan was announced. This plan divided the General College into seven schools, based primarily on different academic disciplines.
The College of Arts and Sciences, created in 1942, consisted of three divisions: the Division of Cultural Arts, the Division of Sciences, and the Division of Social Sciences. The departments within the College of Arts and Sciences were as varied as the divisions, with students able to pursue both Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science degrees in areas ranging from drama and music to mathematics and physics.
The College of Arts and Sciences continued as the central instructional unit of the University of Houston through the mid-1970s. The curricula encouraged students to explore many fields of intellectual interest, while examining one field in depth. In late 1972, President Philip Hoffman appointed a committee to investigate a possible reorganization of the university's administration. One area of investigation was the possible division of the College of Arts and Sciences.
The study found that the areas of responsibility of the Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences were "too broad," making the "offering of dynamic leadership to the college almost impossible because of the numerous departments and special programs, which report to this office." With the recommendations of the study group and President Hoffman, the Board of Regents authorized the reorganization of the College of Arts and Sciences. In 1975 the College of Arts and Sciences was divided into three colleges: the College of Humanities and Fine Arts, the College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics, and the College of Social Sciences.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of twenty-nine boxes of records relating to all aspects of the College of Arts and Sciences. Materials date from 1937 to 1973, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1963 to 1973. While the exact origin of these records is not known, it is assumed that these materials were collected and maintained by the administration of the College of Arts and Sciences. Most of the records bear the names R. Balfour Daniels or Alfred R. Neumann, both of whom held the position of Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences.
Materials in the collection include correspondence, reports, forms, reading files, minutes, and a large variety of other reference and background items relating to the College of Arts and Sciences and its various departments and divisions. The folders appear originally to have been filed alphabetically, and this original order has been maintained or restored when necessary. Within files, items are arranged chronologically, with a few exceptions where an alphabetical arrangement is more appropriate.
This collection reflects almost all the events occurring on the University of Houston campus during this period. Not only are most of the College of Arts and Sciences divisions and departments represented within the collection, but also many programs that had bearing on the activities of the college are represented. University wide committees are strongly represented, numerous national associations and organizations are included, and a variety of local and state issues have materials within the collection. Additionally, the construction of buildings related to the college, including Agnes Arnold Hall, Science and Research I, and the Fine Arts Center, are covered thoroughly.
To gain a complete picture of the campus during this time, the researcher may want to examine other collections with related material, including the President's Office Records and the Business Manager Office Records. The Houstonian, the Daily Cougar, the Board of Regents Minutes and the Historical Photographs Collection may also be of interest.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects
University of Houston Curricula.; University of Houston History.
Subjects (Organizations)
University of Houston; University of Houston. College of Arts and Sciences.
Formats
Correspondence; Minutes; Reports
Detailed Description
- Subject Files (Box 1-29)
  - Academic Advisors Location, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Calendar, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Committee, May 1963-June 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Committee, September-December 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Committee, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Academic Committee, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
  - Academic Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Academic Committee, January-April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Academic Committee, May-December 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Academic Committee, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Academic Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
  - Academic Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10-15)
  - Academic Committee, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Academic Freedom, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Academic Honesty, 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Academic Regalia, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Academic Vice-President Advisory Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Accounting Procedures, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Accreditation Fees, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Acta Diurna, September 1967-August 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Acta Diurna, September 1968-August 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Acta Diurna, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - African Studies, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Afro-American Studies, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American Association of College of Teacher's Education, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1960-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - American Association of University Women, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - American Conference of Academic Deans, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - American Council on Education, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - American Council on Education, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Language Center, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - American Men and Women of Science, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Animal Care Facilities, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Anthropology, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Anthropology Committee, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Art Department, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Art Department, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Association of Higher Education, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Association of Texas Colleges and Universities, 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Band - University of Houston, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Baylor University, 1956-1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Behavioral Sciences Committees, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Biennial Report of the President, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Biology Building - Proposed New, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Biology Department, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Biology Department, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Biology Department, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Biology - Ph.D. Program, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Biophysics Clinical Appointments, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Biophysics Department, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Biophysics Department, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - By-laws - College of Arts and Science, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - By-laws - Colleges - University of Houston, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - By-laws - Colleges - University of Houston, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - By-laws - Departmental, 1962-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - By-laws (Example - Departmental), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Center for Continuing Education, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chamber of Commerce, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Change of Major Procedures, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Channel 13 Building, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chapman College, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chemistry Department, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chemistry Department, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chemistry Department, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chemistry Department, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Classroom and Office Building, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Classroom and Office Building, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Classroom and Office Building (Computer Facility) 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Clear Lake City Center, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Clear Lake City Center, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Clear Lake Graduate Center, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - College of Architecture, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - College of Business, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - College of Education, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - College of Engineering, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - College of Law, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - College of Optometry, 1952-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - College of Pharmacy, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - College of Technology, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Excellence, 1967-1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Bylaws, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Committee on College Development, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Committee on College Government, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Committee on College Government, Annual Reports, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Committees, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Elections, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Faculty and Staff Taking Courses Toward Advanced Degrees, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Faculty-Senate Rapport, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Handicapped Students, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Committee on Student-Faculty, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Teacher Training, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Communications Building, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Communications Department, 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Communications Department, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Communications Department, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Computer Assisted Registration System-Cars, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Computer Assisted Registration System-Cars, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Computer Math Building, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Computer Science Department, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Computer Science Department, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Computer Science Department, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Computer Science Department, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Computing Center-University, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Computing Sciences, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Computing Sciences, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Computing Sciences Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Latin America, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cooley, Dr. Denton Arthur, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cooperative Education Program, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Coordinating Board Advisory Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Coordinating Board Advisory Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Board Forms, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Coordinating Board General, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Coordinating Board General, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Coordinating Board General, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Coordinating Board Report File, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Coordinating Board Report File, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Core Curriculum, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Council of Graduate Schools in US, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Counseling and Testing Services, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Cresap, McCormick and Paget, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Criminal Justice Department, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cullen Auditorium, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Affairs Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cumulative Grade Point Average Committee, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Curriculum Changes, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1954-1962 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Danforth Foundation Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Danforth Workshop, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Data Processing Service, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dean of Faculties Committee Appointments, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dean of Students - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dean's List, 1955-1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dean's List, 1965-1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Dean's List, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Degree Program Requests, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Degree Requirements, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Departmental Chairman's Conference (Galveston), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Del Mar College (Corpus Christi), 1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Development Office, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Director of Research, Francis Smith, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Directory of Visiting Scholars in The United States, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Dissertations and Theses - Format, 1960-1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Distinguished Lecturer, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Doctor of Arts Degree, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Doctor, V.M., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Downtown School, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Drama Department, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - East Texas State University, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Eastern Mennonite College, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Economics-Advanced Degrees Pending, 1955-1970 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Economics Department, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Economics Department, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Education in Germany, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Education in Texas-Hyer Report, April 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Educational Professions Development Act, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Educational Resources Information Center (Relic), 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Educators Report and Fact Sheet, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Electron Microscope, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Elon College (Southern Association of Colleges and Schools), 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - ELS Language Center, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Emory University, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Employee Benefits, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Employment of Aliens, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - English Department, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - English Department, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - English Department, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - English Laboratory, 1963-1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - English Ph.D. Program, 1958-1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - English Ph.D. Program, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - English Proficiency, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Enrollment and Maximum Loads, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1958-1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Enrollment Statistics (Registrar's), 1953-1961 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Statistics (Registrar's), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Environmental Studies, Committee on, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - European Studies, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Excellence Program At University of Houston, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Executive Council, Oct. 1961-August 1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Executive Council, Sept. 1963-August 1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Facilities Planning, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Faculty and Staff in Advance Course, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Assignments, 1967-1971 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Club, 1947-1969 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Development Leaves, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Evaluation, 1959-1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Loads, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Master List, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Master List, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Faculty Master List, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Publications, 1953-1968 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Faculty Recruitment Brochure, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Faculty Representatives of State Colleges and Universities, Meeting of, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Research, General, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Research Support Program, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Roster and Addenda, 1955-1972 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Faculty Senate, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Senate, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Senate, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Senate Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Student Ratio, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Fehlandt, Theordore F., 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fellowships, Scholarships, Stipends, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Fellowships Traineeships - General, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Fields, Emmett, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Final Examinations, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statement - U of H, 1957-1960 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Fine Arts Center, September 1962-August 1966 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Fine Arts Center, September-December 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Fine Arts Center, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Fine Arts Center Building, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Find Arts Center Dedication, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Fine Arts Center Opening, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Fine Arts Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Fine Arts in Texas Research Project, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Five Year Planning - Statistics Lecturer and Teaching Fellow Rates, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Flag Etiquette, 1954-1964 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Fleming Building, 1965-1968 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Florida State University, 1955-1965 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Flower, Dr. John A., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Foley's Scholarship Committee, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Ford Foundation, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Foreign Language Annals, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Foreign Language Conference, University of Kentucky, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Foreign Language Requirements, 1962-1972 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, 1961-1967 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Foreign Languages, Division of, Chairmanship Candidates, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Foreign Languages, French, German, Spanish - Space and Equipment, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Foreign Languages Ph.D. Program, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Foreign Study League, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Study League Vienna, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Forensics, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Forensics, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - French Department, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Enrollment - Fall, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Orientation II, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Freshman Studies, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Friends of Music, Art, and Drama, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Fulbright, 1963-1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Full-time Faculty List, 1962-1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - General Electric - Proposal for College within a College, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Geography Department, 1958-1964 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Geography Department, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Geography Department, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Geology Advisory Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Geology Department, 1963-1968 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Geology Department, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Geology Graduate Program, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Geology Ph.D. Program, 1959-1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Geophysics, 1959-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Geosciences, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - German Department, 1967-1972 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Gifts to the University, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Gordon Fund, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Gourman Report, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Governance Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Grade Distribution, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Graduate Admissions Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Graduate Assistantships and Fellowships at Other Schools, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Graduate Assistantships and Fellowships at University of Houston, 1963-1969 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Graduate Council, 1963-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Council, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Council, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Council, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Council, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Council, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Council, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Council Membership, 1959-1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Graduate English Exams since, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Faculty Nominations, January-August 1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Faculty Nominations, September-December 1970 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Graduate Faculty Nominations, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Graduate Faculty Standards and Selection, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Fellowships and Scholarships, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Graduate Fellowships and Scholarships State Funded Stipends, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Graduate Programs in Arts and Sciences, 1959-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Record Examinations, 1959-1971 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Graduate Scholarships for Needy Students, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Graduate School, 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Graduate School, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Graduate School, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Graduate School of Social Work, 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Graduate Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Graduate Studies Building, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Graduation, 1964-1971 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Grambling College, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Grambling College - Self-study, 1955-1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Growth of Arts and Sciences, 1964-1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Gruppe 47, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Guatemala Summer School, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)